Beyond Journey's End
Episode 36: A Magnificent End
As I thought, this won't be easy.
It's like fighting multiple
master swordsmen at once.
On top of the sheer number of attacks,
his reflexes and stamina
far exceed human levels.
Stark is being overpowered.
If this becomes a battle
of endurance, we're sure to lose.
Should we retreat and regroup?
No, he's faster than us.
He'd chase us down.
This is bad. Frieren was right.
I can't read his attacks.
In that case...
Fool. I told him not to
take his attacks head-on.
You are mine.
He let himself get cut on purpose?
He's one tough kid.
Stark, you're a skilled warrior.
You created the slight opening I needed.
It's over, Revolte.
Wait. I remember now.
You're the partner of the
first-class mage I killed before.
I recall the situation
was similar to this one.
You'd gone off to slay other demons,
while your partner defended the village.
By the time you returned, it was too late.
Don't you want to know
how your partner died?
Silence.
I learned a truly interesting
lesson from that battle.
Enough. I'll silence you myself.
Then I have one last
piece of advice for you.
You should check more
thoroughly for survivors.
A child?
You're just delaying the inevitable.
I did it! I did it, Lord Revolte!
Praise—
Well done. You have my thanks.
My judgment was clouded.
For a moment,
all I could think of was him.
I knew there couldn't be a child here.
I was right. Humans have a habit
of protecting their young.
Do we?
If that were true, the world
would be a more peaceful place.
I only ever knew one idiot who died
protecting a child he didn't know.
Perhaps he was too kind.
It's the same in every era.
Kind mages don't live long.
He met a magnificent end.
So even you say things you don't mean.
Genau, you're an unpleasant man.
You don't have a shred of kindness.
Stay that way forever.
As you wish.
I do not enjoy killing.
I shall put you out of your misery.
I shouldn't have acted out of character.
I'm surprised.
I didn't think there was a warrior alive
who could stop a direct hit from me.
You can still move?
You should've played dead.
Then we would've lost.
Battles are won by whoever's
still standing at the end!
I thought you were a good person,
but you're just an idiot.
That's not a bad philosophy, though.
I shall walk into the jaws
of death with you, Stark.
The more desperate the battle, the more
catharsis you feel when you survive.
I'm looking forward to that.
I can't stop shaking.
What should I do?
Ms. Frieren disappeared at some point.
It's nice to watch from afar
once in a while.
It's pointless trying
to conceal your mana and hide.
I created this fog with magic.
It can detect and identify targets
from the faintest traces of mana.
No living creature can
conceal their mana completely.
Visibility is poor,
and he's blocking my attacks.
It's a bad matchup.
I sense that Ms. Fern
is struggling as well.
It's understandable.
Her opponent seems to be a demon
who uses unconventional magic.
Medrozobalt.
What are you looking at?
I am your opponent.
I know.
Meanwhile, my opponent is the
opposite of "unconventional."
Her combat style is tried-and-tested.
Defending even while she attacks.
Her fundamentals are solid.
She simply has no openings.
I mustn't face her head-on.
Ideally, I'd work with Ms. Fern
to bring both down,
but this fog likely has powerful
mana-detection capabilities.
Currently, Ms. Fern can't use stealth,
her greatest asset.
In which case, the situation would change
greatly if this magic fog were removed.
Shall I cut loose a little?
A flurry of blows?
Her attack pattern changed!
I recognize this fighting style.
It's similar to one used by a clan that
hunted demons on the Northern Plateau.
An insane clan that dedicated
their lives to killing demons.
How interesting.
This should be a good match.
Let's have a fair fight.
He's fast. I can't land any of my spells.
His masterful movements have become
those of a savage predator.
He's still fighting despite the
life-threatening wounds he's suffered.
He has superhuman toughness
and inexhaustible stamina.
At this rate, he really will
kill us through attrition.
Genau, his swords have weakened!
We can break them!
Indeed, he doesn't have the focus to
maintain the mana in his swords anymore.
Three to go!
Wait.
Why does something feel off?
Her attacks are ferocious,
but I sense no bloodlust.
Oh, you really are astute.
But it took you too long to notice.
I've just finished analyzing the fog.
Those who only know how to fight
only learn spells for combat.
Any other member of my clan probably
wouldn't have made it out of here.
Because I doubt they'd
know how fun magic is.
Erilfrachte.
The fog cleared.
How pointless.
I can simply create it again.
Where did that girl go?
Hemmung's mana vanished.
An attack? From where?
Zoltraak.
She's so far—
A super-long-range attack from
outside their detection radius
whose trajectory can't be predicted.
Not bad, Fern. I'm impressed.
I'd rather not fight a battle
this difficult again.
Two to go!
One!
It's over, Revolte.
Only humans think empty hands
can't be weapons on their own.
Your fatal assumption was that I wouldn't
be able to fight if you disarmed me.
I win.
Our fatal assumption? I think you'll find
both humans and demons make those.
For instance, you don't know
how tenacious humans can be.
Cleaving Light!
Digardnacht.
You seem like a good person to me, too.
You're still trying to defend the village,
even after it's been destroyed.
I couldn't do that.
You're still trying to save me.
I knew it.
You're a good guy after all.
Methode.
Did I fail to die again?
It would seem that way.
Enough. I can move again.
How is Stark?
It was a close call, but he'll survive.
I prioritized healing him over you.
I see.
Does that displease you?
No. He did well.
Ms. Frieren's party will be staying
in the village for a while.
Seems like I'm mostly better.
He's doing push-ups.
Could Mr. Stark possibly
be a freak of nature?
That's so mean.
I noticed your party
doesn't have a priest.
I'll be free for a while
once this job is over.
Shall I accompany you?
The Northern Plateau is dangerous
without priest spells.
We'll be fine.
I can't cast anything high-level
like healing magic,
but I know a few priest spells.
If we find ourselves in serious trouble,
we can always run away.
That's what we've done until now.
Besides, we want to keep
our priest slot open.
We might see him again someday.
And...
For some reason, Fern seems
unhappy when you're around.
Oh, my. I've made her hate me.
But I also love you, Ms. Fern.
You're so cute when you're angry.
Methode.
The Chivalric Order of Norm have arrived.
We'll be accompanying
them back to the south.
Understood.
This is where we say goodbye.
Stark, how are your injuries?
All good. No problem.
I see.
I owe you all a debt.
One I intend to repay someday.
Mr. Genau.
You're forgetting something.
Thank you for your help.
No, thank you.
I hope both of us live long lives.
Let's go.
Yes, sir.
See you later.
Yeah.
May our paths cross again.
Was it really the right move
to turn her down?
Methode, I mean.
This party's priest is Sein.
No, I mean she's a pretty older lady.
Won't Sein complain
when we see him again?
Who cares? This party
already has an older lady.
I guess that's true.
Translation
Sho Stifler
Editing & Typesetting
Geoff Mazzolini
Subtitle Timing
Edgar Cruz
Quality Check
Alicia Ashby
Translation Check
Elizabeth Ellis
It'll depend on the pay.
Do dragons not normally travel in flights?
That's some terrible luck.
We're the party of heroes.
I'm so bored, I could die.
That's a tall order.
I've looked up to him since I was a child.
What's written in it?
Episode 37
Himmel's Memoirs
Himmel's memoirs...