Beyond Journey's End
Episode 31: Somewhere She'd Like
29 years after the death of Himmel the Hero,
in the Etwas Mountains, located in the northern lands
It's gotten warm lately.
This is a volcanic area.
It's an unusually warm region
within the northern lands.
Which means we can finally
enjoy some hot springs.
That's right. We'll probably
arrive at the next village soon.
We can take a dip there.
Hey, Frieren. We've been
walking for a while.
Are we there yet?
The village should be around here.
I see a cabin.
Just one building.
I have a bad feeling about this.
Wait, mister!
Hurry up!
Wait for me!
This brings back memories.
The village was abandoned
over thirty years ago.
The hot spring dried up, so the
adventurers stopped coming.
One at a time!
That's a shame, isn't it, Ms. Frieren?
Human villages always vanish the
moment you let your guard down.
We'll have to wait until the next town
to enjoy the hot springs.
How far is it to the next town?
About a week's journey.
So we have to wait a whole week.
Are there no other
hot springs around here?
Come to think of it,
I heard from my grandfather
that there's a hidden hot spring
in the mountains back there.
That was over thirty years ago, though.
It's the hidden hot spring
of the Etwas Mountains.
You're familiar with it?
I doubt it's still there.
It's pretty deep in the mountains.
We'd probably reach a hot spring sooner
by just heading to the next town.
What is it, Mr. Stark?
The hidden hot spring of
the Etwas Mountains...
I feel like I've heard those words before.
Oh, I remember now.
Frieren, I think I'd like to visit
the hidden hot spring.
Mr. Stark?
Stark, even though it's technically a hot
spring, it's really not worth the trouble.
After all, it's—
We came all the way here already.
Let's go check it out.
Fine. If you really want to go, let's go.
Later, mister!
Let's play again!
Later!
We're almost at the hidden hot spring.
Ms. Frieren, you don't seem very excited.
I guess not.
I wandered through the mountains
in search of the hidden hot spring
with Himmel and the others.
I want to go home.
Me, too.
You traveled there with
Mr. Himmel's party, too?
Himmel wasn't satisfied until he searched
every nook and cranny of an unusual place.
You said it'd be quick!
I'm telling you, there's something here.
I can feel it in my gut.
I told you so.
There's no turning back now.
The road to the hidden hot spring
is especially brutal.
You have to pass through the territory
of a troublesome monster.
It's here already.
Let's do this.
A dragon, huh?
It's been a while.
That's not a dragon.
If anything, that monster
is closer to being a lizard.
A lizard?
It's quite agitated.
That's typical of monsters
when their territory is invaded.
You have to cut off all three heads at
the same time, or they'll regenerate.
Seriously?!
Run, Stark.
I have a plan.
What kind of—
We'll split up to the left and right
and attack all three heads at once.
Understood.
Let's do this in as few
attempts as possible.
If our timing is off,
it'll keep regenerating.
Um...
The plan you mentioned earlier...
We'll strike while the monster
is attacking Stark.
You mean...
I was just the bait.
Good work, both of you.
We're finally here.
That was difficult.
See? I told you we should've just
headed to the next town.
That's the hidden hot spring
of the Etwas Mountains.
It's so shallow.
This is just a foot bath.
I told you it wasn't worth the effort.
This is fine.
This way, we can all enjoy it together.
You're right.
This is a nice view.
Yeah.
By the way, Mr. Stark,
why did you want to come here?
I heard about it from my master.
The hidden hot spring of the Etwas
Mountains was just a foot bath.
It wasn't worth the effort at all.
It was a truly ridiculous adventure.
It's strange, though.
I wouldn't trade my memories
of those ridiculous adventures
with my friends for anything.
I'll never forget that view.
So you knew, Mr. Stark.
I think I wanted to see the
same view my master saw.
It really is a nice view.
The way back is brutal, too.
Maybe it wasn't worth
the effort after all.
29 years after the death
of Himmel the Hero,
in the fortress city of Heiß,
located in the northern lands
You sure love hot springs
for someone so young.
Yeah!
Dang it!
Next game!
Ms. Frieren has been soaking in the
hot springs ever since we arrived here.
When she does come out,
it's just to visit magic shops.
Apparently, we're staying
for two more days.
I guess that's a short stay for Frieren.
I made sure to give her an earful.
We have nothing to do
all day tomorrow, though.
You're right.
Maybe I'll visit a weapon shop.
I need to get my axe sharpened.
Okay, but I'll have nothing
to do all day tomorrow.
Pay attention to me.
You're so inconsiderate, Mr. Stark.
Seriously? You didn't
have to put it like that.
She's always so hard on me.
Fine. It's time for some payback.
If you're that desperate for attention,
let's go on a date tomorrow.
Oops. This never goes well.
I'm dead.
Very well. See you tomorrow.
Um, your book...
Why'd she react like that?
Excuse me...
Frieren...
What do you think? Is she mad?
What's going to happen to me?
Stark, do you understand
who you're asking for advice?
Have you lost your mind?
You're right. Sorry for
asking the impossible.
I never said it was impossible.
I'm a grown woman, you know.
I know exactly how a girl thinks.
Are you sure? I'm trusting you.
Okay, let me ask you again.
Frieren, if I said to you, "Let's go
on a date," what would you think?
You've grown into a fine man, Stark.
I'm so happy, I might treat you to dinner.
Yeah, this isn't helping.
This feels like a grandma
hanging out with her grandson.
You just called me a grandma.
That's your second offense
after calling me a hag.
You won't get away with a third.
Why are you counting? You're scaring me!
By the way, what happens
on the third offense?
I'll scream and cry.
My tantrums are scary, you know.
They even made Himmel the Hero
tremble with fear.
She's been crying for three
full days and nights.
Yikes.
Terrifying.
That sounds terrifying.
Is that how a grown woman behaves?
Well, I understand now that you're
entirely lacking in tact and sensitivity.
So, are you going on a date with Fern?
It doesn't feel like
I can take it back now.
So I thought I'd ask you to suggest
some places she might like.
Actually, never mind.
I shouldn't have asked—
Should we go take a look, then?
What?
I can probably find somewhere.
Somewhere she'd like.
What should we do now?
Why don't we get something to eat?
Good idea.
You should start by getting her
something to eat at the market.
She gets cranky when she's hungry.
Don't skip the food stalls.
Fern has loved snacking
since she was little.
She'd probably like shops
with pretty items on display.
Fern likes baked goods, but what
she wants depends on her mood,
so you should choose a few dessert shops.
What else...
Quiet plazas like these
are an option, too.
Seriously? You know Fern really well.
I'm impressed, Frieren.
No, I don't know anything.
I'm not impressive.
Heiter was the impressive one.
He talked about Fern's
preferences all the time.
"She gets cranky when she's hungry,"
"she likes snacking,"
"she likes pretty things,"
and "her preferences change depending on
her mood" are all things Heiter taught me.
Heiter seemed to want me to be
a parental figure to Fern,
but ultimately, I failed
to discover anything she liked.
But you remember all of that.
I think you're a good parent to her.
Come to think of it,
we first celebrated Fern's birthday
on the road in a place like this.
You have some nice things
to say sometimes, Stark.
I know, right?
I'll strike one offense from the record.
Thanks...
Ms. Frieren, I was asked out on a date.
What should I do?
You, too?
It's nothing.
Ms. Frieren, have you
ever been on a date?
I have.
Of course you haven't.
Wait, you have?!
Yeah.
Who did you go with, and what did you do?
Himmel and I went looking for a lost cat.
We were asked to by the owner
of a magic item shop.
So you were just completing a job.
I'm not sure you can call that a date.
Listen, Fern,
when two close friends of opposing sex
go out with each other and nobody else,
that's a date.
That's what my master said.
Come to think of it, I went
on a date with Sein, too.
Forget it.
Good night.
Translation
Sho Stifler
Editing & Typesetting
Geoff Mazzolini
Subtitle Timing
Edgar Cruz
Quality Check
Alicia Ashby
Translation Check
Elizabeth Ellis
So you're the first-class mage Fern.
I wasn't expecting to find
such a powerful monster here.
You're not wearing your usual clothes.
So, where are we going?
I thought I was going to die.
We were born and raised here.
Don't let your guard down.
I want to protect
other people's homes, too.
Episode 32
Other People's Homes