Beyond Journey's End
Episode 35: The Divine Revolte
Genau's partner died
in battle the other day.
So you'll be slaying demons together
on the Northern Plateau for a while.
I look forward to working
with you, Mr. Genau.
The Northern Plateau is as dangerous
as you'd expect the farthest
reaches of the north to be.
Don't hold me back.
Now shake hands.
Methode, do you think
you are a good person?
I don't understand what you're saying.
My previous partner was a good person.
The exact opposite of me.
He'd try his hardest
for complete strangers.
He was always so boisterous,
so full of smiles.
He treated me as casually
as an old friend,
and his personality naturally
drew people to him.
He was a fool.
He died protecting a child.
Because of that,
we failed to kill the demon.
I'd never do anything so stupid.
I've forsaken countless people already.
Why me?
What do you mean?
Why was I chosen to work with you?
Who knows? It was Ms. Serie's decision.
All I can say is that first-class mages
who get dispatched to the Northern Plateau
are usually the type that loves fighting
more than three meals a day.
It certainly is strange.
Why you, and not Übel?
Either way, no decent
person likes fighting.
Don't end up like me.
Let's share what information we have
before we begin our search.
Very well.
Based on traces of magic
and other evidence,
there are four primary demons
who attacked the village.
All four have vanished from the area.
Four? That's a lot.
One of them was a demon general.
It killed the knights with four swords.
What exactly is a demon general?
A highly skilled and experienced
demon warrior.
They fight by enhancing their physical
capabilities with powerful magic.
Some are devotees who spend hundreds
of years perfecting their martial skills.
Some of the generals in the Demon King's
army were far stronger than Eisen.
Seriously?
Also, it's likely that it has
a far-from-human appearance.
Is that bad?
Have you ever fought an expert swordsman
who wields four swords at once?
Of course not.
Me neither.
That's probably why the knights lost.
Lord Revolte.
Our prey has been caught in our net.
They're a tasty meal, rich in mana.
One warrior, four mages.
Three are first-class.
We can handle that many.
Shall we attack?
No.
I have a bad feeling about them.
We'll wait for them to split up.
Do you think they will, Lord Revolte?
They seemed rather guarded.
They will.
That's why we provoked them
by killing all those people.
In the course of destroying all these
villages on the Northern Plateau,
I've noticed something.
Ooh, what is it?
Let's go look for the demons.
We'll head to the abandoned fort
to the north first.
Demons often hide out
in places like that.
Wait.
The Chivalric Order of Norm
still needs to collect the bodies.
Someone should stay
in the village until then.
I'll remain behind.
Humans have a habit of remaining
in villages to protect their corpses.
How interesting. Why do they do that?
We don't need to know the reason.
I wonder why, though.
I'm so very, very curious.
You're interested in humans?
You're a strange one.
Humans sometimes behave
illogically and irrationally.
I want to know why they do that.
That's just how they are.
There's nothing more to it.
We don't need to know why.
Come to think of it, I've heard of an
eccentric demon who studies humanity.
Really? Tell me more about them, please!
If you make yourself useful, I will.
You will? Then it's a promise,
Lord Revolte!
You'll stay by yourself?
They shouldn't be much longer.
I'll meet up with you once the
Order has collected the bodies.
Fine.
I'll stay, too.
Are you stupid?
Your party is heading out to fight demons.
What will they do without a front-liner?
The same goes for you.
What if the demons return to the village?
It won't be a problem.
I can fight well enough
without a front-liner.
So can Frieren and the others.
There's only so much
we can handle, though.
But if things look bad,
you can run, right?
I guess so.
You can't run away, though.
You'd be abandoning the village.
Stark. All that's left here is the dead.
And that's who you're staying
to protect, right?
Suit yourself.
Stark, you're a good person.
I've known people like you.
They tend not to live long.
You seem like a good person to me, too.
You're still trying to defend the village,
even after it's been destroyed.
I couldn't do that.
I'm not a good person.
Quite the opposite.
I've done whatever it took to
bring peace to the northern lands.
I've killed and forsaken many people.
Perhaps this is what I deserve.
You get used to people dying, you know.
I don't feel even slightly sad.
My hometown's been destroyed,
but I feel nothing.
I'm only staying in this village
because I thought I should.
I've forsaken so many in the past,
so what am I even doing?
Stark, many people call
the Northern Plateau home.
From now on, avoid using
long-range detection.
If they're skilled, they
can trace it back to us.
Okay.
That said, we still have a ways
to go before we reach the fort.
Let's talk while we walk.
Should we be doing that?
It's important to ease the tension.
She looks so careless.
Also, communication improves teamwork.
I bet you didn't know that.
I see.
In that case, Ms. Frieren, may I pet you?
Is she actually saying that
with a straight face?
I love giving headpats to small girls,
but Ms. Serie doesn't let me do it often.
Not only that, but she always
looks so displeased when I do.
I would, too.
And besides, I'm the older
one here by far, Methode.
I won't suffer headpats
from the likes of you.
That's right. Ms. Frieren
is a mature lady.
Don't think you can casually touch her.
Ms. Frieren.
This contains a spell
that prevents pieces of shell from
falling in when cracking eggs.
You can pet me all you want.
Ms. Frieren?
I can't believe you're allowing me
to pet you this much.
No more than ten minutes per day.
But...
Ms. Frieren, may I hug you a little?
Ms. Serie never let me.
You can do whatever you want.
Whatever I want?!
Huh? What?
Hey, stop.
You'll tear me in half...
Is this...?
We've been detected.
They know where we are.
That's demons for you.
They're aggressive.
They must know we're skilled mages,
but that doesn't faze them.
They noticed.
I see. Shall we begin?
Nebeladora.
It's a fog made of mana.
They're blocking our vision
and mana detection.
We've been separated from Methode.
They're skilled.
Which one do you want?
The tall one has an
unusual aura about her.
She should be fun.
Then I'll take the other two.
Watch out for attacks from above.
Ms. Frieren.
What?
Both demons were flying.
So were the demons we fought before.
That's flying magic, isn't it?
I told you.
Until forty years ago,
demons ruled the skies.
They haven't lost those skills.
But you said demons only
study one type of magic.
Do you think of walking
as a special ability?
It's the same principle.
To demons, flying magic isn't even magic.
That's why this is a common sight
when fighting them.
As I thought, they're
accustomed to battle.
They fight like members
of the Demon King's army.
Methode has engaged the enemy.
Fern, you'll handle the fighting.
Why?
This job was assigned
to the first-class mages.
You're the first-class mage here.
Ms. Frieren, is now
really the time for that?
It won't be a problem. You can beat him.
See?
Oh?
That was just a fluke.
I only reacted in time
because you pointed.
I couldn't detect his attack at all.
He's better than me.
I disagree.
Not many first-class mages are as
dedicated to the fundamentals as you.
It's all right. You can beat him.
I caught some fish.
How about a late-night snack?
I'll pass. Methode will be angry with me.
She says it's unhealthy
to eat late at night.
Oh, yeah? More for me, then.
I always get hungry at this hour.
Don't tell Fern.
Sure.
You seem to be dealing with a lot, too.
Hey, Genau.
You know the demon who attacked
this village, don't you?
Demons that fight with four
swords are hardly common.
The Divine Revolte is the
demon who killed my partner.
That's a grandiose name.
It comes from the four swords
he created using magic.
He can freely change
the weight of his swords.
Sometimes they're sharp
and light as a feather.
Sometimes they're as heavy as a boulder.
They're called the Divine Cleaving Swords,
after the blade that split mountains
during mythical times.
So they're both light and sharp
and unbelievably heavy.
It's contradictory, isn't it?
Magic can create objects
that shouldn't exist.
In particular, weapons made from magic
are the embodiment of murderous intent.
Demons that create such
weapons kill many people—
far more than necessary,
as if to test them.
Stark.
I know. It's the enemy.
It's fast.
Here it comes.
Four swords!
One warrior and one first-class mage.
As I predicted,
you're protecting the village.
That's Revolte.
This is him?
You seem to know who I am.
That first-class mage
in particular looks familiar.
Who are you?
Let's begin, Stark.
Avoid taking his attacks head-on.
Worst case, it could destroy you.
I said, who are you?
Do you declare your name
before exterminating a pest?
You're one twisted person.
We're both capable of speech, are we not?
But if you don't wish to talk...
then I, too, shall focus on
exterminating the pests before me.
What am I supposed to do
if I can't take his attacks head-on?
A warrior can deflect blows, can he not?
Yeah, but...
I can't protect you like that!
I don't need protecting.
Despite how I may seem,
I'm skilled in close-quarters combat.
Demon magic isn't the only magic capable
of producing objects that shouldn't exist.
Digardnacht.
A spell to manipulate niello wings.
Interesting.
Translation
Sho Stifler
Editing & Typesetting
Geoff Mazzolini
Subtitle Timing
Edgar Cruz
Quality Check
Alicia Ashby
Translation Check
Elizabeth Ellis
It's nice to watch from afar
once in a while.
It's a bad matchup.
She simply has no openings.
I can't read his attacks.
I did it!
This should be a good match.
It's pointless trying
to conceal your mana and hide.
I shall put you out of your misery.
Episode 36
A Magnificent End
He met a magnificent end.