Are you sure this is far enough?
It's fine. I'll make the rest
of the journey alone.
Besides, my destination
is only accessible on foot.
Very well. Take care.
Beyond Journey's End
30 years after the death of Himmel the Hero,
in the Drachen region, located on the Northern Plateau
This looks bad.
The village was attacked by a dragon.
They even have dragons
on the Northern Plateau?
This really is a dangerous place.
It could be worse.
What?
When I traveled with Himmel, we were
attacked by a flight of dragons.
I can't even imagine a whole flight.
That's crazy.
Um... do dragons not
normally travel in flights?
Was this village attacked by a flight?
Yes. One moved in nearby.
I'd like you to slay them.
The Northern Plateau's
normal is terrifying.
That's super crazy.
This village is done for.
You should move somewhere else.
But this is our home.
Be careful.
Are you okay?
I'll bring it to you now.
He's right, Ms. Frieren.
That was a cruel thing to say.
I feel sorry for the villagers.
Do you understand what it means
to face a whole flight of dragons?
There's no way we'll come away unscathed.
We protect people's homes.
Right, Frieren?
It'll depend on the pay.
Our village is very poor.
We have nothing to pay you with.
You don't have any grimoires?
Only one for a terribly
useless spell that allows you
to say tongue twisters without
tripping over your words.
That does sound useless.
Doesn't matter as long
as it's a spell, huh?
Do you know where
the dragons came from?
Somewhere in those woods.
We'll search for traces of mana.
We may be able to track them.
We continue straight here.
I've been thinking this for a while now,
but magic sure is amazing.
It's really convenient
at times like these.
Keep the praise coming.
Mr. Stark, carelessly praising her isn't
good for Ms. Frieren's development.
I guess that's true.
What do you two think I am?
In any case, I can tell roughly
which way they are. Let's go.
There they are.
That's a lot of dragons.
But they're small ones.
They won't be nearly as strong
as that solar dragon.
That said, dragons are smart.
Don't let them surround you.
Let's draw them to one spot
and take them down all at once.
Stark, keep them locked down.
You're an experienced
dragon fighter, right?
Again? That's a tall order.
Shall we begin?
You'd better actually
fire some spells this time.
As long as you don't end up
slaying them all first.
That was a ridiculously intense battle.
It's a good thing this
village has a church.
You even got your head
chewed on during the fight.
How are you not in worse shape?
I don't know.
That's probably normal for warriors.
Eisen was fine after getting
his head bitten, too.
No, Mr. Eisen is definitely
as far from normal as it gets.
I hope you weren't waiting long.
Thank you. Here's your
grimoire as payment.
Come to think of it, you almost always
demand payment for helping people.
Because that's what Himmel did.
I'm surprised.
I always assumed he was someone
who helped others for free.
I know. I used to think the same thing.
Thank you so much.
You deserve more, but as you can see,
our village is poor.
This is all we have.
We can't accept food from this village.
Is that a grimoire?
Actually, it's a notebook we received from
a traveling merchant some time ago,
but we have no use for it.
Himmel, why do you demand payment
nearly every time we help someone?
If they pay us,
they don't owe us anything.
We're the party of heroes.
What we want is to help people,
not words of gratitude.
If we make people indebted to us,
we haven't really helped them.
That's why I even take ridiculous
spells like this as payment.
Frieren...
I'm going to see if it really works later.
In the end, you just want spells.
Couldn't you get a spell that
prevents dragon bites instead?
Episode 37: Himmel's Memoirs
How's it look outside, Frieren?
Looks like we won't be able
to head out for a while.
That's some terrible luck.
I can't believe we're stuck here.
I'm so bored, I could die.
That's less the boredom
and more the hangover.
Cheer up, everyone.
We're on an adventure
to defeat the Demon King.
We haven't been able to
adventure for days now.
Adventures aren't just about
strolling around in the great outdoors.
Sometimes, an adventure can just
be a bunch of crappy days in a row.
You're the only one calling it crappy.
What are you doing, Himmel?
Is something the matter?
No...
30 years after the death of Himmel the Hero,
by Lake Korridor, located on the Northern Plateau
It's been a week since
we arrived in this city.
The weather's as stormy as ever.
Will you be able to take
the ferry out today?
Does it look like I can?
My boat isn't a coffin, you know.
I suppose not.
I gotta say, though. I'm surprised
even lakes can get stormy.
Lake Korridor is the largest body
of water in the northern lands.
It's larger than some inland seas.
Yeah, we can hardly see the far shore.
Also, large mountain ranges to the
east and west disrupt air currents,
making this time of year
hellishly stormy.
It's not unusual for even large
ships to sink in these storms.
With these winds, we can't use
flying magic to cross, either.
It would be difficult to fly across
even on a clear day.
The far shore is farther than you think.
I might be able to make it,
but you don't have enough mana.
Could we go around the lake?
That would be difficult, too.
Why?
The terrible weather is caused by...
the mountain ranges to the east and west.
Trying to cross a stormy mountain range
without even a mountain pass...
would be suicide.
Waiting here for a few months
is ultimately safer and quicker
than trying to find a way around.
Fortunately, this is a fairly large
port city and trading hub.
It's the perfect place to pass the time.
We ended up waiting all winter.
Can you take the ferry out today?
Yeah.
Can you pay, though?
The storms may have passed,
but it's still not a safe journey.
I expect to be paid appropriately.
That's not nearly enough.
This is your fault for buying
too many grimoires, Ms. Frieren.
I had a lot of time on my hands.
In that case, we can exchange favors.
On an island just off shore,
there's an abandoned monastery
that's protected by a barrier.
Himmel the Hero's memoirs
are said to be there.
Himmel the Hero saved this city
during my grandfather's time.
I've looked up to him
since I was a child.
Everyone in the city wants those memoirs.
I'd like you to find them.
Himmel's memoirs...
Come to think of it,
he said he'd lost the memoirs
he'd been working on during our travels.
He was pretty disappointed, I think.
I can't believe that's where they were.
Sure, we'll take the job.
Is that a whole fleet of ships?
It's like we're out at sea.
Yes. Many people and shipments of goods
traverse the lake this time of year.
And lately, there have been
rumors that a Golden Land,
where anything and everything is made
of gold, was found in the north.
More people are crossing
the lake than usual.
A Golden Land? Is that true?
Who knows?
But I've never met anyone
who's actually been there.
It's probably just a tall tale.
That's the island.
The barrier isn't very strong.
Well, it seems to be several decades old.
This is a grand monastery.
Why was it abandoned?
The roof caved in after a monster attack.
It was an old building.
I see. That's why they erected
the barrier in a hurry.
What do you mean?
Most monasteries keep
old and valuable books.
Huh.
So the barrier was for protecting the
books they couldn't take with them.
It's open. Let's search the monastery.
What happened to the monks who were here?
Who knows? It was abandoned
a long time ago.
The only knowledge that remains is the
story about Himmel the Hero's memoirs.
This is a big library.
There's a statue of Mr. Himmel.
That's a handsome pose.
Here we are.
This is it.
Yup. This is definitely it.
This is Himmel's handwriting.
What's written in it?
It's the everyday minutiae
of a ridiculous journey.
Just everyday stuff.
Here. This is what you asked for.
Now our fare is paid in full.
I heard an elven mage traveled
with the party of heroes,
but I never thought I'd get to meet her.
What made you think it was me?
After seeing that wistful look
on your face, how could I not?
That's something important to you,
isn't it? You should keep it.
There are plenty of other
valuable books here.
That's more than enough payment.
Did it really show on my face?
Only a little.
Come on. We'll reach the
far shore before sunset.
I'm not sure we'll need this
collection of cool catchphrases.
It's a waste of pages.
Maybe I'll use one next time.
"Come at me, monster! I, Stark
the warrior, shall take you on!"
Huh?
It's a kraken!
There are sea monsters here, too?!
You provoked it.
It's my fault?!
Stark, if we don't defeat it quickly,
it'll drag us all to a watery grave.
Ms. Frieren!
Frieren!
Stark, this monster's weakness is—
Huh? What?
And that's how you two can now
take it down. Good luck.
Ms. Frieren seems to be using
the spell that allows you
to say tongue twisters without
tripping over your words.
What?
How are you two so calm? It's scary.
Translation
Sho Stifler
Editing & Typesetting
Geoff Mazzolini
Subtitle Timing
Edgar Cruz
Quality Check
Alicia Ashby
Translation Check
Elizabeth Ellis
It's a 3,000 meter drop.
The risk matches the reward, huh?
It's beautiful.
It's reacting to our mana.
If we defeat the Demon King,
a time will come when anyone
can enjoy this beautiful sight.
Episode 38
A Beautiful Sight