Beyond Journey's End
That's a really deep canyon.
I can't even see the bottom.
30 years after the death of Himmel the Hero,
by the Great Tor Canyon, located on the Northern Plateau
It's a 3,000 meter drop.
This is the deepest canyon
on the continent.
It's only possible thanks to the
Northern Plateau's elevation.
So how are we going to cross this?
The wind is quite strong.
We won't be able to fly across with magic.
I feel like we just dealt
with something similar.
If we head upstream,
we could cross the river,
but we'll have to pass through
a treacherous mountain range.
It's a pretty big detour.
What about downstream?
There's also a 3,000 meter cliff
facing the sea.
It's quite beautiful, apparently.
Would you like to go see it?
No, thank you.
Either way, at this rate, it'll take us
two weeks to cross the canyon.
That's a long time.
It's not like we have a choice.
Well, it might be finished soon.
What do you mean?
For now, let's head upstream.
If we're lucky, we might be able
to cross over on our way there.
Ms. Frieren.
It's coming into view.
Wow. Is that a bridge?
Yeah. Looks like he's finished it.
Gehen.
It's been a while, Frieren.
You successfully completed your bridge.
Yeah.
Who is he?
Gehen, the dwarf who's been building
this bridge for the last 200 years.
That's amazing.
I'm surprised, though.
A bridge this well-made
should be a major crossing.
But I haven't heard anything about it,
so I thought you hadn't finished it yet.
There's actually one problem, Frieren.
As you can see, large bird monsters have
been stirring up powerful gusts of wind.
A group of merchants headed
for the so-called Golden Land
was blown over the other day,
wagon and all.
Not only that,
but the monsters keep coming.
They've built a large nest nearby.
In doing so, they've rendered
my bridge useless.
Fortunately, the nest is
somewhere on this side.
Could you do something about it?
I spent 200 years building this bridge.
What will you pay us?
A spell that lets you
flip pancakes perfectly.
I have the ingredients, too.
You could enjoy a grand
breakfast tomorrow.
You have a deal.
According to Gehen,
it should be around here.
This path is quite precipitous.
Be careful. If you fall, you're finished.
By the way, why did Gehen build a bridge
across this canyon in the first place?
Probably out of regret.
So the bridge is still under
construction. That's too bad.
When will it be finished?
I'm not sure it ever will be.
I ran out of funds.
It's a shame, when I have
all the time in the world.
Gehen, why were you
building a bridge here?
My village used to be around here,
but it was attacked by demons.
The closest army was stationed
in a city across the canyon.
If this bridge had existed then,
everyone could've been saved.
Use this.
It's the reward we received for reclaiming
a noble's treasured sword from demons.
This is a lot of money.
I can't accept this.
I don't have anything suitable
to offer in exchange.
You have this bridge.
It won't be finished until after you've
died of old age, at the very least.
Then Frieren will accept your repayment.
Build it strong enough
to last a thousand years.
Fine. You can count on me.
Here they are.
Let's defeat them.
Gehen.
We took care of the monsters.
Thank you, Frieren.
Now people can freely cross the canyon.
What are you going to do now?
I plan to spend my old age
quietly in my village.
What?
Hey, he's back.
Good timing.
That's great news, Gehen.
Let's celebrate tonight.
Frieren.
Two hundred years is more than enough
time for a village to be built anew.
I see.
Shall we go, then?
Episode 38: A Beautiful Sight
30 years after the death of Himmel the Hero,
on the Schmal Snowfield, located on the Northern Plateau
What's up?
We're nearly out of travel funds again.
Oh, yeah?
I'm not sure we can survive
even a week on this.
Honestly, it's because
you keep wasting money.
Either way, we can't do much
in the middle of this snowfield.
Wait. Isn't this place...?
We're changing course. I might know
a place where we can get money.
What is this?
It's not a village.
Is it an adventurer camp?
All right, boys! Give it
everything you've got!
Yeah!
What is this place?
A camp for adventurers
seeking holy snow crystals.
Holy snow crystals?
A mineral produced in the
snowfields of this region.
They're used to create magical potions.
They're a valuable resource that can only
be mined here, so they fetch a high price.
I see.
In other words, we'll earn travel funds
by finding those holy snow crystals.
You're still so naïve, Stark.
Holy snow crystals aren't something
you can just stumble upon.
That's why they're expensive.
Then how are we going to make money?
Let's check out the marketplace
that caters to the adventurers.
You'll see something interesting there.
It looks like an ordinary
marketplace to me.
Look at the prices.
One silver for a loaf of bread.
That's more than ten times
the market price.
They're selling to wealthy adventurers
who make money mining holy snow crystals.
So the prices are much higher here.
I see.
Holy snow crystals are expensive
for two reasons.
The first is their rarity.
The second is because they're found in a
dangerous region full of savage monsters.
Do you see where I'm going with this?
If prices are up, then rewards for
monster slaying must be up, too.
Right as always, Fern.
There's a large mineral vein
here known only to locals.
I'd like you to defeat the
monster dwelling there.
Also, I'd like you to erect an
anti-personnel barrier once you finish.
An anti-personnel barrier?
Yes, so no one can enter.
Got it. We'll take the job.
An anti-personnel barrier
is an unusual request.
It takes time to gather the manpower
and funds required for mining.
It's not unusual for people to claim
spots using anti-personnel barriers
so that others don't take them.
In any case, let's go slay this monster.
We found it.
It's big.
Don't let your guard down.
They only would've put out a job
to slay this monster
if none of the adventurers
at the camp could handle it.
If you get careless, you'll die.
The risk matches the reward, huh?
Let's take it down.
It's reacting to our mana.
That's annoying.
This thing's fast.
Stark.
Run.
I have a plan.
You can count on me.
Higher.
That monster really was strong.
Ms. Frieren?
Quiet.
What's going on?
That monster was the lord of this area.
Other monsters sensed its mana
weakening and gathered here.
What should we do, Frieren?
I still have the energy
to carry you two and run.
It's too late.
We're surrounded.
Either way, we'll have to defeat
all of them to complete the job.
Do you have enough mana?
I'll be fine.
We don't have a choice.
The Chivalric Order of Norm.
We pursued those monsters here
due to their ominous behavior.
We didn't realize it was you.
Thank you. We appreciate the help.
We should be thanking you.
We received word from Mr. Norm.
You've done a lot to help us.
Now we're even.
Farewell.
They rode all the way out here.
That's incredible.
That squad patrols their entire territory.
The Northern Plateau
is changing little by little.
It's long past sunset.
We'll camp here tonight.
Ms. Frieren, it's morning.
Please wake up.
Just five more hours...
You'll freeze to death.
Anyway, look.
The holy snow crystal vein looks beautiful
in the light of the morning sun.
You're right.
Our goal this time was
only to earn travel funds.
I wasn't expecting to encounter
such a feast for the eyes.
It's beautiful.
This is worth defeating
the Demon King for.
If we defeat the Demon King,
a time will come when anyone
can enjoy this beautiful sight.
Though not anyone can come here,
we've entered an era in which
many people can see this sight.
It feels strange.
It really is beautiful.
Yeah.
And yet, it'll soon be torn
down by human hands.
It's a bit sad, but time marches on.
Let's erect the barrier in a bit
and then head back.
Thank you for your help.
Here's your reward.
Now we can preserve that vein.
Preserve it? The barrier's
not for mining it later?
I'm an adventurer from this region.
And seeing that beautiful sight was
what inspired me to become one.
Thank you. Because of you, I can
protect the sights of my homeland.
I see.
It's a good thing,
protecting other people's homes.
Yes, it is.
Now that I think about it, maybe
Mr. Heiter protected my home, too.
Though I lost my home to war,
thanks to him, I kept
my precious memories.
Me, too.
When I told you I fled from my home,
you said that didn't matter
and believed in me.
Come to think of it,
you're always encouraging me.
Why is that?
Because that's what Ms. Frieren would do.
Translation
Sho Stifler
Editing & Typesetting
Geoff Mazzolini
Subtitle Timing
Edgar Cruz
Quality Check
Alicia Ashby
Translation Check
Elizabeth Ellis
Ms. Frieren, why did you buy a magic
item here when prices are so high?
You can't find stuff like this everywhere.
We'll be short on money for a while.
I thought this might happen
and hid half our funds.
Seriously?
You never let me down, Fern.
This is why you're my student.
You're okay with that?
Shall we go, then?
This is Edel, a second-class mage.
She's an expert in mental magic.
I brought her here to reexamine the area.
I believe the information she acquired
will be very useful to you.
Denken, give me your hand.
I'll transfer the memories to you.
Sure.
The handover is now complete.
Your job is to maintain and manage
the barrier around the Golden Land.
Do not stray from your duties.
Denken.
Give up on visiting her grave.
I know.
He intends to die.
I'm a bit jealous.
I can't defy Ms. Serie's orders.
He's up against the last and strongest
of the Seven Sages of Destruction,
Macht of the Golden Land.
And he'll fight him to save
his gold-turned homeland.
He's like the hero in a fairy tale.