Beyond Journey's End
Episode 32: Other People's Homes
Ms. Frieren, which do you
think would be better?
What difference does it make?
Also, can you do my hair
before you go out?
Please stop.
I'll apologize, okay?
Just don't braid out of anger.
If you're that desperate for attention,
let's go on a date tomorrow.
Shall we go?
Okay.
You're not wearing your usual clothes.
Why is that?
Didn't you say this was a date?
Right.
I was so surprised!
Oh, please!
Huh? Has Fern always been this cute?
A-Anyway, let's go.
Mr. Stark, your movements
seem quite forced today.
No, they're not.
What is it?
So, where are we going?
There's a marketplace.
Let's go check it out.
Come to think of it, Ms. Frieren
visited it several times.
Yeah. She said sometimes markets in
big cities have unusual magical items.
Wow. Amazing.
So that's why there was a mountain
of odd magical items at the inn.
Sheesh.
I can picture that disaster.
The other day, she even fell asleep
under a pile of magical items.
What?
It'd be kind of scary at that point.
It was.
Do you think Frieren is visiting
the hot springs again today?
Surely she's tired of it by now.
Yeah. She's been going
every day recently.
And today, she didn't tie her hair up.
So good.
You've gone with a cute
hairstyle today, miss.
We always end up talking
about Ms. Frieren.
It's not like there's
anything else to discuss.
Take a look! I'll give you a discount!
Do you want to get something to eat?
No, not yet.
I see...
Look.
Apparently couples get a discount.
Being on a date has its benefits.
You're rather blunt, aren't you?
Anyway, all this stuff is pretty ordinary.
I'd be surprised if they
were all magical items.
You have a point.
Since we're in a city, let's check
out some other places, too.
This is cute!
Hey, nice.
Could I get this, miss?
Sure thing.
Thank you.
You're a couple of lovebirds, huh?
You must be hungry by now, right?
There were some stalls selling
tasty-looking food over there.
Here you go.
These look so good.
There are tables over there.
Right.
Whoa.
Are you okay?
I'm sorry.
It does seem hard to walk in those shoes.
There are statues of
Mr. Himmel in every city.
His pose in this city
was pretty handsome, too.
It was.
According to Frieren, there are
over a hundred different poses.
They made a few too many, didn't they?
Seriously.
We ended up talking about
Ms. Frieren again.
Anyway, this is a nice, quiet place.
The view is pretty, too.
Yeah.
Fern, did you not have fun today?
I wouldn't say that.
You haven't smiled once.
Well... I did like all
the places we visited,
but for some reason...
it didn't feel like you.
I was looking forward to our date, too.
Sorry, Fern.
I actually had Frieren
choose those places.
Why would you do that?
Because I really wanted you to enjoy it.
We've never been on a date before,
so I wanted it to be special.
I see.
True, I was slightly disappointed
by today, but...
I'm also very happy.
You really racked your brain for me.
Fern...
This is such a peaceful, quiet moment.
Doesn't that cloud look familiar?
It's one of the pork buns we ate earlier.
I was thinking the same thing!
It's strange.
When I was a war orphan, I never
thought I'd get to relax like this.
Yeah.
I have Mr. Heiter to thank for that.
And I have my master to thank.
You won't become a strong
warrior if you're picky.
Hey, Master.
What is it?
Why did you take me in?
Because it's what Himmel
the Hero would've done.
You seem to be in a good mood.
Did something good happen?
Not really.
So it wasn't here either.
I'm stumped.
We searched everywhere
the shopkeeper could think of.
Himmel, why are you smiling?
I'm in a good mood
because today was a good day.
All we did was walk around
looking for a lost cat.
Yes, but I had fun going out with you.
Even though we never found the cat?
Even if things don't go as you'd hoped,
you can still enjoy the process.
That alone is enough to put
someone in a good mood.
Huh.
Okay.
Let's give it another shot before
Heiter and Eisen beat us to it.
There it is, Himmel.
That must be it. Let's catch it!
Your hair's braided again.
These are the braids I get
when Fern's in a good mood.
I can't tell the difference.
Well? Don't I look good?
I really can't tell the difference.
29 years after the death
of Himmel the Hero,
in the Nachricht region,
located in the northern lands
It's gotten cold again lately.
We're out of the volcanic area now.
We should be able to see it soon.
Is that the Northern Plateau checkpoint?
It's so imposing.
Because what's beyond it
is just that dangerous.
We probably won't have decent
access to supplies for a while,
so let's get everything we need.
That suitcase fits more
than it looks like it would.
Convenient, right?
So you're Fern, a first-class mage.
Take care.
I guess Fern's pretty impressive.
First-class mages are
the greatest of all mages.
So this is the Northern Plateau.
It seems pretty normal, considering
how dangerous everyone said it was.
Are you being serious, Mr. Stark?
What do you mean?
We're surrounded.
Look sharp.
This is just the beginning.
It's a village.
I thought I was going to die.
We did have to stay alert
for three days and nights.
I hope we can rest here.
That's fine.
There's a cabin nobody's using.
Feel free to use it.
Thank you.
I hate to ask, but in exchange...
A powerful monster started frequenting
the main road past here.
The local knights are
powerless against it.
Traveling merchants can
no longer pass this way.
As you can see,
adventurers rarely visit this land.
Would you please slay
that monster for us?
Sure. We're going north anyway.
We'll slay it on our way.
You're okay with that, right?
Yes.
Sure...
But it's just a three-day trip south
along the main road
to leave the Northern Plateau.
There's no need for you to live
in this dangerous place, is there?
This area is certainly dangerous,
even by the northern lands' standards.
But we were born and raised here.
The land is full of our
memories of our families.
Who could abandon their home?
Let's go.
We're counting on you.
This must be the monster.
Don't let your guard down.
I can't get a clear shot.
It's different from the others.
This seems like a formidable foe.
The methods we've been using
won't work against it.
It certainly seems that way.
In that case...
Oh, it noticed me.
Stark, lock it down.
Got it!
It's tough, but so am I!
I won't let it beat me!
Frieren!
That thing was pretty strong.
We've still only just entered
the Northern Plateau.
Going forward, we'll face
loads of monsters that strong.
You mean things like that
are all over the place?
That will be difficult.
Hey, Frieren.
Maybe we should've traveled
by sea after all.
I think it'd be worth the price.
I wasn't expecting to find
such a powerful monster here.
I thought I was going to die.
If it's going to be this dangerous, we
should have sailed around the whole area.
That's why we came this way.
Many people live on the Northern Plateau.
I became a hero because
I wanted to protect my homeland.
So I want to protect
other people's homes, too.
Stark, many people call
the Northern Plateau home.
You're right.
Let's do our best.
Fire yourselves up for the road ahead.
Yes, Ms. Frieren.
We made it through that fight
thanks to Stark's last-ditch effort,
but we'll have to focus more
on teamwork going forward.
You're right.
By the way, Stark,
why are you still sitting?
I'm not sitting.
My legs gave out.
Pathetic.
I can't help it!
I thought that crazy spell
was going to kill me!
Translation
Sho Stifler
Editing & Typesetting
Geoff Mazzolini
Subtitle Timing
Edgar Cruz
Quality Check
Alicia Ashby
Translation Check
Elizabeth Ellis
Don't come crying to me later.
So that they don't end up like me.
Seriously, what am I going to do?
All we can do is buy back Ms. Frieren.
Let go!
I did it for that legendary liquor.
The president told us about you.
Of course I do.
Episode 33
Logistics in the Northern Plateau
Logistics in the Northern Plateau.