Beyond Journey's End
29 years after the death of Himmel the Hero,
in the Bier region, located on the Northern Plateau
I guess there are cities
on the Northern Plateau.
There are a lot of bars here.
This area's the only grain-producing
region on the Northern Plateau.
It's always had plenty of breweries.
Huh.
I was talking to Old Man Fass.
He said he's almost found Boshaft.
Really?
He's been talking about that
since my grandpa was a kid.
What's Boshaft?
I've heard about it from Mr. Heiter.
Long ago, most of the continent was
ruled by a single great empire.
It was an exquisite liquor
offered to the emperor.
Huh.
He would lament about how, because of
Ms. Frieren, he never got to drink it.
There was a reason for that.
I don't want to stay here for long.
Once we're finished shopping—
Frieren!
It's you, Frieren!
I haven't seen you in a century.
It's been eighty years, Fass.
You're a stickler for details now?
How unlike you.
Your roster's changed.
That young guy who liked
to drink isn't with you?
Heiter's dead.
He went peacefully.
I see. I was too late.
I've located Boshaft,
the Emperor's Spirits.
Will you help me?
You can use magic, right?
What does magic have to do with Boshaft?
Come with me, and you'll see.
It's in here.
Is this... a mine?
I dug it all by myself.
Most people think all dwarves are miners,
but I grew up in the city.
I had to study mining from scratch.
I did it for that legendary liquor.
Who is this old guy?
Fass. No one loves liquor as much as him.
He's spent over two hundred years
looking for Boshaft.
He asked us for help
the last time we met,
but we had a Demon King to defeat
at the time, so we said no.
But Boshaft!
Let go!
Pulling Heiter away was no mean feat.
Why are you digging a mine
to find liquor?
According to legend, there's Boshaft
stored in the ruins underground here.
And two hundred years ago,
when I found this stone monument,
I knew it was true.
This is ancient elvish.
The inscription proclaims that Boshaft is
the greatest liquor to have ever existed.
"Milliarde."
Perhaps that's who wrote
this inscription.
You're well-educated if you can
read ancient elvish at your age.
Ms. Frieren drilled it into me
when I was young.
Most grimoires are written
in ancient elvish.
You'll have to learn to read it.
So it was Milliarde.
Ever since discovering this inscription,
I've dedicated my life to finding Boshaft.
And now, it's almost within my grasp.
You found the ruins?
The ruins themselves, yes.
But as you can see, the doors to
this stone chamber won't open.
A powerful barrier was erected
to preserve the liquor.
You should be able to break it, though.
I can't.
Surely you can.
It'll take time to remove.
Those kids wouldn't be happy about that.
I'll make it worth your while.
With a grimoire?
Money! I'll pay you twenty
Reich gold coins.
That's not even worth considering.
Please, Frieren!
It's my dream to drink Boshaft!
I've been searching for
over two hundred years!
No.
Ms. Frieren, perhaps we could help him.
Yeah. I feel sorry for Old Man Fass.
What's this about?
You're giving me the creeps.
Normally, you'd be opposed
to this sort of thing.
Ms. Frieren, he's offering twenty gold
coins. We can use that on our journey.
That's a ton of money.
We won't have to worry about
living expenses for a while.
What?
But the barrier will take
three months to remove.
That's hardly any time at all.
What?
We'll do it.
Don't come crying to me later.
We're in the final stages
of removing the barrier.
We should be able to finish tomorrow.
You don't look very pleased.
I guess not.
Boshaft doesn't taste good.
It's not worth devoting your life to.
But the inscription said...
Some elves pass the time
in ways you wouldn't believe.
Milliarde, you never do anything.
You just gaze off into space.
Many of our fellow elves spend their
long lives searching for something.
Why do you think that is?
Why?
So that they don't end up like me.
Frieren, could you imagine the thing
you spent your life searching for
turning out to be worthless garbage?
Not at all. What are you talking about?
My distant past.
This liquor really is terrible.
Boshaft.
That's the awful, cheap liquor
they served at the coronation.
Before coming to this village,
I carved an inscription to pass the time.
It says, "Boshaft is the greatest
liquor to have ever existed."
What was the point of that?
There was no point at all.
It's finally time.
It's well-preserved.
I never thought I'd get to taste this.
Let's toast. Drink with me.
This is...
Frieren, why did you decline
to search for Boshaft?
Heiter, you like liquor, right?
Of course I do.
Listen to this corrupt priest.
What would you do if the liquor
you spent your life searching for
turned out to be unbelievably terrible?
Well...
I think I'd laugh it off.
It tastes bad, right? Then it's
best enjoyed with friends.
It's so...
It's terrible.
It's the worst-tasting drink
I've ever had.
Why are you just watching? Try it, Stark.
What? No way. It's terrible, right?
Just try it.
It's freaking gross!
Why is it so gross?
It really is terrible.
Try it.
There's plenty to go around!
I'll make the whole city suffer with me!
Frieren.
My search ended in disappointment,
but I've never had such a fun night.
I'm glad you guys were here.
Liquor's meant to be
enjoyed with good times.
Episode 33: Logistics in the Northern Plateau
30 years after the death of Himmel the Hero,
in Norm Company territory, located on the Northern Plateau
Here's your share of bread, Mr. Stark.
Did you hear that?
This bread just went "clunk."
That's not a sound food should make.
We've been eating rock-hard
bread this whole week.
Don't complain.
The Northern Plateau is barren outside
of the grain-producing Bier region,
and goods aren't even circulating now.
We'll be eating mostly this while
we camp, at the very least.
That's so sad.
If we walk another half day,
we should be able to get a decent meal.
That's an impressive fortress city.
That's the Norm Company's estate.
That structure in the center
is their headquarters.
They deal in various goods,
primarily wheat from the Bier region.
They're an armed trading company
with the logistics network
and military force to supply the villages
dotted across the Northern Plateau.
Not even the state can touch them.
For all intents and purposes, they rule
humanity on the Northern Plateau.
But Ms. Frieren, you said earlier
that goods aren't circulating.
That's the problem.
I don't know the specific cause,
but things change over time.
Maybe the Norm Company
isn't as strong as it once was.
But it's likely that they still have a lot
of influence on the Northern Plateau.
We should avoid making waves.
I see.
So you're Ms. Fern, a first-class mage.
You may pass.
That person...
One moment, please.
I wonder what's going on.
I am Norm, the company president.
Ms. Frieren, mage of the party of heroes,
you will be paying off the debt
you've owed for eighty years in full.
Ms. Frieren, you've been carrying debt?
Just a little.
Seriously?
But I was told I could
pay it back anytime.
That's not what the documents say.
Verbal agreements are no good.
It seems my predecessor's predecessor
was lax in that area, but I am not.
Three Strahl gold, twenty Reich gold,
and various silvers and coppers.
You're as wealthy as a minor noble.
Right?
Your grandfather did us a favor,
so you can keep the change.
I see.
This isn't nearly enough.
Anyway, I have to work in the mines
for three hundred years.
My journey ends here.
What are you talking about, Ms. Frieren?
Why are you dressed like that?
Where's your bag?
They took everything as collateral.
Bye, Fern and Stark.
Take care.
What?
What are we going to do?
All we can do is buy back Ms. Frieren.
She's not a thing, you know.
Unfortunately, there's nothing
you can do about it.
Take a look.
According to the documents,
she owes over five hundred Strahl
gold coins including interest.
Even when converted to Reich gold coins,
the most trusted currency on the Northern
Plateau, she owes over three hundred.
Do you think you can procure such a sum?
No, that would be impossible.
Seriously, what are we going to do?
We can't wait three hundred years.
I don't really like mines.
They're hot and dusty.
The president told us
about you, Ms. Frieren.
I see.
Shall we get started, then?
We'll go straight through here.
You're certain?
Who do you think I am?
All right, boys! Start digging!
Yeah!
The Norm Company president
of two generations ago
started out as a backwater noble
cast out to the Northern Plateau.
He was a great man who invested in this
barren land and built a logistics network,
bringing stability to people's lives.
At the time, nobody expected
much from our party of heroes,
but he provided us with funds
with no repayment deadline.
I never thought I'd be treated
like this by his grandson.
But there must be a reason you came
all the way to this mine, right?
Logistics in the Northern Plateau
are in a terrible state, aren't they?
I suppose.
Even my companions complained that
they'd never eaten such hard bread.
I'm sure they hadn't.
I'm not fond of it either.
Since conditions have worsened here,
we've lost a third of our armed
caravans and army fighting demons.
Our logistics network is in ruins, too.
If the Norm Company were a nation,
we'd have fallen already.
However, we are a trading company.
As long as we have the funds,
we can always rebuild.
When you arrived in this region, I felt
the Goddess must've brought you here.
That scrap of paper representing your
party's debt gained tremendous value.
This mine is still under development.
If we strike silver ore,
we'll turn a huge profit.
Enough to forgive the party
of heroes' debt and more.
It should be easy for you
to find, Ms. Frieren.
I see. So you're using that
scrap of paper to coerce me.
If our logistics network falls apart
entirely, many people will starve and die.
Please save the people of the
Northern Plateau, Ms. Frieren.
Also, if you help us, you'll
have soft bread to eat
even in the farthest reaches
of the Northern Plateau.
You're as shrewd as your grandfather.
This is why I can't stand merchants.
Fine. You have a deal.
Either way, I intended to repay
the debt I owed your grandfather.
I can't believe we
actually struck silver.
I'm back. Shall we go?
Oh, good. We were discussing
how to save you.
We were planning to raid the mine tonight.
Sheesh. You're so hot-headed.
More importantly, from now on,
we'll get to eat soft bread.
Huh? What does that mean?
Translation
Sho Stifler
Editing & Typesetting
Geoff Mazzolini
Subtitle Timing
Edgar Cruz
Quality Check
Alicia Ashby
Translation Check
Elizabeth Ellis
I was worried to death.
I'll help you bury them.
Protect the villagers!
Someone like that can't be saved.
We were a bit too late.
Demons destroyed the village...
There are so few of them.
Are you praying?
So Ms. Fern also received
a demon-slaying request.
Episode 34
A Demon-Slaying Request